最好最坏打算  这些人危险至极
Expect the worst. These guys are beyond dangerous.
行动
Let's go.
别动  举起手来
Don't move! Show me your hands!
你就带来这么点人吗
Is that all the guys you brought?
你还好吗  孩子
How you holding up, kiddo?
这分居真是越来越烦人了
This separation thing is getting really old.
我知道
I know.
但凯瑟琳现在处于十字路口
But Katherine is at a crossroads.
她年轻时的丧亲之痛
The loss she suffered when she was young
改变了她
has just changed her in ways
而她现在才开始发现改变有多深
that she is just now beginning to realize.
要不要妈妈主动给你点建议
Can your mother give you a little unsolicited advice?
-不要  -那太遗憾了
- No. - Too bad.
我需要推敲材料
I need to work on my material.
-推敲材料  -我没说过吗
- Your material? - Didn't I tell you?
我在写书
I'm writing a book.
《主动忠告》  玛莎·罗杰斯著
"Unsolicited Advice" by Martha Rodgers.
这简直
That's...
这还真是个好主意
That's actually a great idea.
是啊  是吧
I know. Isn't it?
你的代理人也很喜欢
Oh, and your agent loved it, too.
-我代理人  -别管那个了
- My agent? - Never you mind that.
听好
Just listen.
有点信心
Have faith.
你和凯瑟琳之间的事
Things between you and Katherine
一般都会自行解决
have a tendency to just work themselves out.
我觉得她离开
I think it's probably good
几天或许也是好事
that she's out of town for a couple of days
你正需要与她分开一段时间
because a little time apart is just what you need.
我需要个办法分分神
What I need is a distraction.
被称为纽约最
The burglary at what has been labeled
安全的大楼发生的盗窃案显然
New York's most secure building is clearly a black eye
打了亿万富翁开发商雷纳德·布斯的脸
for billionaire developer Ronald Booth,
他仍未透露具体被盗了什么
who's keeping quiet about exactly what was stolen
但之前发表了这一番言论
but had this to say earlier.
欢迎来到理查德·卡塞尔侦探社
Welcome to Richard Castle investigations.
你出落得不错啊
You grew up nice.
抱歉  我们认识吗
I'm sorry... do I know you?
我是你爸的老朋友  伊森·斯勒特
Old friend of your dad's... Ethan Slaughter.
当然了
Of... of course.
我去告诉他你来了
Yeah, let me just tell him you're here.
一级警备  斯勒特来了
Defcon one. Slaughter is here.
来这儿了
Here?
就在门后吗
Like, right behind the door here?
嗯
Yeah.
-他想干什么  -我不知道
- What does he want? - I don't know.
他只说是你的老朋友
He just said he was an old friend.
这绝不是好事
That can't be good.
这是几年前
Is that the old friend
差点害死了你的老朋友吗
who almost got you killed a few years ago?
嗯  六次呢
Yeah, like six times.
好吧
Okay,
我能应付的
I'll... I can... I can handle this.
我...
I'll just...
我去告诉他
I'll just tell him...
我去告诉他我不感兴趣
I'll just tell him I'm not interested in,
不管他是有什么事
uh, in whatever he... whatever it is.
大侦探  好久不见啊
Hey, Sherlock. Long time, no see.
斯勒特
Slaughter!
伙计  你好吗
Buddy. How you been?
枪战太少  其他都好
Not enough shootouts, but otherwise, stellar.
嗯
Yeah.
这里是没有枪战的
You're not gonna find many shootouts around here.
见到你真高兴
So, good seeing you.
你改日再来啊
You should come back again sometime.
别急  我们有事要商量
Oh, not so fast. We got some business to discuss.
什么事
What kind of business?
夫人  我们好像没有幸见过吧
Ma'am, I don't believe we've had the pleasure.
少跟我来这套  亲爱的
Don't "Ma'am" me, darling.
我是玛莎·罗杰斯  理查德·卡塞尔是我儿子
I'm Martha Rodgers. Richard Castle is my son.
你俩上次一起办事时
And the last time you two did business together,
他不得不吃了一个月的抗焦虑药
he was on antianxiety medication for a month.
她开玩笑的  真逗
She's kidding. Kidder.
就几周而已
It's just... it was just a few weeks.
你真是有位虎妈啊  大侦探
Well, you got a real mama lion here, Sherlock.
但不必担心
But no reason to worry.
我要找你办的事绝不会害你涉嫌的
What I'm here about won't put you in a lick of danger.
我保证
I promise.
是什么事啊
And what's that?
我在办的案子需要人帮忙
The case I'm working on and need help with...
是一栋市中心的高级大楼的盗窃案
a high-end burglary in this big, shiny building in midtown.
纽约最安全大楼吗
The most secure building in New York?
我刚在新闻里看到
I just watched a news report about it.
看来有人绕过了警报系统
Yeah, seems, uh, somebody was able to bypass the alarm system
偷走了什么绝密微型芯片
and steal themselves some sort of top-secret microchip.
这事以我的智商有点理解不了
The whole... the whole thing's above my intellectual pay grade,
所以我想着大侦探可以帮帮忙
so I thought Sherlock here could help me out.
你不是黑帮特遣队的吗
I-I thought you were gang task force.
那个干腻味了
Oh, yeah, I got tired of that.
我开始搞新一级别的混蛋了
I moved on to a whole new class of dirtbags.
多谢你来找我
I-I'm flattered you thought of me,
但是...我日程都满了
but I'm just... I'm... I have my... my schedule is so full.
-我们可忙了  -一点时间没有
- Yeah, we're swamped. - Completely swamped.
真的
Completely.
好吧
Okay.
你不用说两次  我懂的
You don't have to tell me twice. I got it.
很高兴再见到你  大侦探
Great to see you again, Sherlock.
我还有些故事本想告诉你
I had some stories I was gonna tell you
好帮你写新书
to help you with your next book,
有次我追着一支毒贩集团攻击队
like this time I was chasing this cartel hit team
在下水道里追了三天
through the sewers for three days.
看来只能下次再说了
But that's just gonna have to be for another time.
再见
Ciao.
贩毒集团攻击队
Cartel hit team?
坚定点  理查德
Be strong, Richard.
还是在下水道里
In sewers?
斯勒特
Slaughter!
等等
Wait!
我加入
I'm in.
太棒了
Outstanding.
第一步做什么
What's our first move?
下东区  我一个熟人  维克多·李
Lower East Side... guy I know named Victor Lee.
被害人名叫维克多·李
Victim's name is Victor Lee.
男性  30岁
30-year-old male.
死于失血
Died of exsanguination
由于脖子里被插了把刀
From that giant knife in his neck.
昨晚10点到凌晨2点间被杀
Killed between 10:00 and 2:00 last night.
好吧  看看被害人在跟谁通话
All right. Let's find out who the victim was talking to.
他脸上的淤青呢
What about that bruising on his face?
那个更早
That's older.
看来这24小时内有人折磨过李先生
Looks like someone worked Mr. Lee over within the last 24 hours.
能从凶器上提取到指纹吗
Any hope of getting a print off that murder weapon?
恐怕不会  看上去似乎是擦过
Doubtful. Looks like it's been wiped clean.
埃斯波
Hey, Espo.
猜猜被害人最后打给的是谁
Guess who the last person our victim called was.
知道我现在多么
Do you know how hard it is
拼命忍着不说"你妈妈"吗
for me to not say "your mama" right now?
斯勒特
Slaughter?
我哥们怎么了
What the hell happened to my guy?
卡塞尔  斯勒特
Castle. Slaughter.
我可没想到会看到你俩一起出现
This is not a pairing I would have expected.
可不是
I know, right?
我是说  又聚首了哦
I mean... together again!
好诶
Yay!
有线索吗
You got any leads?
嗯  被害人昨晚给你打过电话
Yeah... we got our victim calling you last night.
想说说你俩谈了什么吗
Care to share what you talked about?
维克多是我的线人
Victor was my C.I.
我手里最好的告密鬼
Best damn snitch I ever had.
他根本不是罪犯  他是个汉堡餐馆的经理
'cause he wasn't a criminal. He managed some burger joint.
但跟一群人渣一起长大
But he grew up with a rogues' gallery of lowlifes,
他们蠢得忍不住不跟他吹嘘
and they were just too stupid not to keep bragging to him
他们犯下的各种罪行
about all the crimes they were committing.
他打给你做什么
So, what was he calling you about?
他在打探我调查的一桩盗窃案的消息
Ah, he was doing some digging on this burglary I'm investigating.
看来他是因此被杀了
Well, looks like that digging might have got him killed.
你是说这是我的错吗
Are you saying this is my fault?
除了你  维克多还向别人告密吗
I-- well, was Victor talking to anyone else besides you?
不  他说要去见个什么人
No, he said he was gonna go meet someone.
但没告诉我名字
He didn't give me that name.
那么我们第一步就是找到那人
All right, then, our first step is to identify that guy.
不  那是我们的职责  这是凶案组的案子
No, that's our job. This is a homicide investigation.
怎么地  先是我的案子的  维克多是我的人
Tough! It was my case first. Victor was my guy.
我们要一起找到杀了他的那个鼠辈
So we're gonna find the rodent that killed him together.
走吧  大侦探
Come on, Sherlock.
好吧  但是  斯勒特
All right, but, Slaughter,
你们做什么都得告诉我们一声
you're gonna keep us in the loop on every move you make.
当然了
Of course.
我最懂得配合了
I'm a team player.
我完全是骗他们的
I totally lied to those guys.
我已经有
I already got a line on
维克多昨晚见的人的线索了
who Victor might have met with last night.
你不觉得这消息该跟
Don't you think that's information we should share
莱恩和埃斯波西托分享吗
with Ryan and Esposito?
不
Nah.
这多好玩
Isn't this fun?
你我又再次联手
You and me together again.
就像虎豹小霸王
Like Butch and Sundance.
你应该知道电影最后他俩死了吧  对吗
You know they die at the end of the movie, right?
知道  但死得多酷啊
Yeah. But what a way to go.
我无法相信  我昨天还有和他说话
I can't believe it. I just talked to him yesterday.
你和他说了什么
What did you talk to him about?
重新在一起
Getting back together.
我们几个月前分手了
We broke up a few months ago.
我厌倦了他的说话不算话
I got sick of him not keeping his word.
但是他说这次会有所不同
But he said it was gonna be different this time.
告诉我他马上能挣一大笔钱
Told me he was about to come into some big money.
我们在讨论一起离开
We were talking about taking off together --
去加利福尼亚
California.
我一直想住在海滨
I always wanted to live on the beach.
他有没有说这笔钱会从哪来
Did he say where this big money was coming from?
没有
No.
可不可以请你稍等片刻
Would you excuse us for a second?
你觉不觉得维克多可能和那个微型芯片
Do you think Victor might have been involved
失窃有关
in stealing that microchip?
不可能  他是个老实人
No way. He was a straight arrow.
我知道你欣赏这个人
I know you liked the guy,
但是他做着最低工资的工作
but he was working a minimum-wage job
而他周围违法的哥们都日进斗金
while all his criminal buddies were pulling in big cash.
你真的觉得他不可能
Is it so impossible to believe
屈服于这样的诱惑吗
that he might have given in to temptation?
好吧  这有可能
Yeah, it's possible.
我只是不愿相信他耍了我
I just hate the idea he was playing me.
维克多有提过昨晚他要和谁见面吗
Did victor say who he was meeting with last night?
一个叫特鲁科的人
Some guy named Trucco.
我查了一下斯勒特手里的盗窃案
So, I looked into Slaughter's burglary case.
盗贼偷走了
The burglars made off with
一个用于下一代手机的微型芯片
a microchip for a next-gen cellphone.
原型在黑市上价值超过一百万美元
Prototype is worth north of a million bucks on the black market.
维克拉姆正在已知黑市贩数据库里
Vikram is looking in the database of known fences
找处理这类赃物的人
to find out who deals in that kind of loot.
鉴证组在凶器上找到了一枚指纹
Yo. CSU managed to find a print on the murder weapon.
藏在刀柄下面
It was hidden under the hilt of the knife.
他们在系统里找到吻合的了吗
They get a match in the system?
找到了  他们在发过来
Yeah, they're sending it now.
过来了
Here it is.
怎么了
What?
好  知道了
Yeah. Got it.
找到特鲁科了
Found Trucco.
他是个专营高科技的黑市贩
Turns out he's a fence specializing in high tech.
我们去问问他如何
What say we go shake his tree?
听起来不错
Sounds good.
卡塞尔
Castle.
-你在哪  -在办公室
- Where are you? - At the office.
斯勒特和你在一起吗
Is Slaughter with you?
在啊
Yeah.
听着  卡塞尔  凶器上有他的指纹
Listen, Castle, his prints were on the murder weapon.
斯勒特杀了维克多·李
Slaughter killed Victor Lee.
一切都好吗  大侦探
Everything okay... Sherlock?
-你在和谁通话  -就我妈咪  妈妈
- Who you are talking to? - Oh, just my mommy -- mother.
只是我  只是我妈妈  抱歉  妈妈
Just my...just my mother. I'm sorry, mother.
你刚才说什么
What were you, uh, what were you saying?
我们正在往你那里赶
We're headed to you right now.
你要去俱乐部  还有多久到哪里
Oh, you're going to the club. Uh, how long till you get there?
我们还有五分钟就到
We are five minutes away.
所以保持淡定
So just play it cool.
对  不要让他知道你在和我们通话
Yeah, don't let on that you're talking to us.
好  没问题
Yeah, no problem.
那不是你妈妈
That ain't your mom.
是拉丁猫王和幸运符  对不对
It's Elvez and lucky charms, isn't it?
出了点小问题
There's a slight problem.
把电话给我
Give me that phone.
你是谁  G型神探吗
What are you, Inspector Gadget?
这是把枪  不是支笔
This is a gun, not a pen.
你不该把它放在桌子里  应该带在身上
You don't keep it in your desk. You strap it to your side.
或者对你来说  放在你的小提包里
Or, in your case, keep it in your purse.
请不要杀我
Please don't kill me.
-我不会杀你  -你把刀插进维克多脖子里
- I'm not gonna kill you. - Is that what you told Victor
前也对他这么说的吗
before you buried a knife in his neck?
不是我干的
That wasn't me.
那为什么凶器上全是你的指纹
Then why were your fingerprints all over the murder weapon?
我送那把刀给维克多是为了谢谢他
I gave Victor that knife as a thank-you.
致谢礼
A thank-you gi--
鲜花是不错的致谢礼物
Flowers are a nice thank-you gift.
一把大号兰博刀  简直神经病
A giant rambo knife -- that's psychotic.
做法不同  不过这是事实
Eh, different strokes. But it's the truth.
那么把你自己交给那哥俩
Then just turn yourself in to the boys.
他们会公正处理的
They'll treat you fairly.
没那么简单
It ain't that simple.
昨天早晨当维克多拒绝给我调查
I may have hit Victor a few times yesterday morning
那起盗窃案的时候我可能打了他两下
when he wouldn't look into that burglary for me.
但我没有杀他
But I didn't kill him.
一个拿枪指着我的人这么说
Says the man holding a gun on me.
给你  拿着
Eh, here. Take it.
拿着
Take it!
我之前没有告诉你
I didn't tell you any of this before
是因为我知道这看起来是什么样
'cause I know how it looks.
你毫不犹豫就相信我杀了维克多
You didn't doubt for a second that I killed Victor.
其他人也不会犹豫
Neither will anyone else.
所以唯一能证明我清白就是找到真正的凶手
So the only way to clear my name is to find the real killer.
所以
So...
为什么来找我
Why come to me?
因为我敌人很多
'cause I got a lot of enemies.
却没有一个朋友
What I don't got's a friend.
我需要一个朋友  大侦探
I need a friend, Sherlock.
斯勒特在哪
Where's Slaughter?
他走了  几分钟前离开了
He's gone. He left a few minutes ago.
-发生了什么  -他坚称自己是无辜的
- What happened? - He insisted he was innocent.
说那把刀是送给维克多的礼物
Said he gave that knife to Victor as a gift.
礼物  为什么不送一瓶好酒
A gift? What's wrong with a nice bottle of wine?
就是
I know!
不过  伙计们  我得告诉你们
But, guys, I got to tell you
他看上去说的是真的
he really seemed like he was telling the truth.
别想了
Forget it.
那人说个一个字都不能信
You can't trust a word what that guy says.
你应该比谁都清楚这点  卡塞尔
You, above all people, should know that, Castle.
他出格被抓
It was only a matter of time
只是时间问题
until he crossed the line and got caught.
你能活下来完全是运气
You're just lucky to be alive.
离他远点
Stay away from him.
我不喜欢对他们撒谎  不过你说得对
I do not like lying to those guys, but you were right.
他们不会相信你的
They're not gonna give you the benefit of the doubt.
你是个好人  大侦探
You're a good man, sherlock.
现在我们是绑在一根绳上的蚂蚱
Now we're neck-deep in this together.
我们最好开始行动
Well, we better get to work.
莱恩和埃斯波西托是优秀的警察  他们会找到你
Ryan and Esposito are good cops. They're going to find you.
好吧
All right.
我们去把特鲁科吊在窗户外面直到他开口
Let's go hang Trucco out a window till he talks --
或者我们失手
or we lose our grip.
走吧伙计
Vamos Muchacho.
这人在哪
So, where is this guy?
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
我的线人告诉我他会在这里出现
My source says he'll be here.
你那性感的老婆
Hey, any chance that smokin' wife of yours
会不会也来追捕我
is gonna come hunting for me, too?
如果是她来铐我那还算值了
Might be worth getting caught if she does the cuffing.
不会  贝克特和我现在暂时分开了
Um...no, Beckett and I are sort of on a time-out right now.
真是遗憾
Oh. Sorry to hear that.
谢了
Thanks.
发生了什么
So, uh, what happened?
我不知道
I don't know.
她只是说她需要时间来想清楚一些事
She just said she needed time to figure things out.
女人
Women.
是啊
Yeah.
如果你想找人治愈心伤
If you're looking for a rebound,
我表妹肖娜有个慕男狂的室友
my cousin Shauna's got a nympho roommate.
不用了  谢了
Um...I'm good -- I can -- I'm good, thanks.
好吧  随便你
Well, all right. Suit yourself.
-没有什么比放手更能让女人回心转意  -好了
- Nothing makes a woman want you more than moving on, - Okay,
-对吧  -对话到此为止
- though, right? - conversation's over.
以及  还有
And -- and -- and another thing.
这次  是你有求于我
This time, you need me.
所以我们得按我的规矩来
So we're gonna play by my rules.
那是什么规矩
And what rules are those?
你不能伤害任何人
You're not gonna hurt anybody.
你不能恐吓任何人
You're not gonna intimidate anybody.
以及  你不能提高你的音量
You're not even gonna raise your voice.
如果你做了  那我就退出
You do, and I'm out.
你在开玩笑  对吗
You're kidding, right?
没有
No.
好吧  成交
Okay. Deal.
特鲁科
Trucco!
到了付出代价的时候了  伙计
Time to pay the piper, buddy.
我刚才说什么了
What did I just say?
抱歉  特鲁科先生
My apologies, Mr. Trucco.
我是斯勒特警探  这位是卡塞尔
My name is Detective Slaughter, and this is Castle.
我们想和你谈谈维克多·李
We'd like to have a little chat with you about a Victor Lee.
没听说过他
Never heard of him.
特鲁科先生
Mr. Trucco...
我们都知道你以贩卖高科技产品为生
We both know that you fence high-tech items for a living
而且你和维克多·李有交易
And that you had a deal with Victor Lee
要替他卖掉一块他偷来的微型芯片
to move a certain microchip that he stole.
除非你想让我们去搜你家
Now, unless you want us to go check out your place
看能不能找到什么赃物
and see if we can find any stolen merchandise,
我强烈建议你告诉我们想知道的事
I strongly recommend you tell us what we want to know.
你们想知道什么
And what's that?
你昨晚有没有从维克多那买来一块偷的微芯片
Did you buy a stolen microchip from Victor last night?
没有
No.
蠢货  看我把你的脸撕下来
Ass clown, I'll tear your face off.
伙计
Dude!
拜托  先生  告诉我们事实
Please, sir, tell us the truth.
我说的是实话
I am.
维克多和他的搭档
Look, Victor and his partner were
昨晚约好跟我见面  但是他们没出现
supposed to meet me last night, but they never showed.
-他的搭档是谁  -我不知道
- Who's his partner? - I don't know.
不过从维克多跟他说话的口气上看
But from the way Victor talked about him,
他们的搭档关系不会再维系多久了
it seems like they weren't gonna be partners for long.
你和我想的一样吗
You thinking what I'm thinking?
可能不是
Probably not.
可能维克多想独吞
Like, maybe Victor got greedy
想要出卖他的搭档
tried to double-cross his partner?
然后搭档把他干掉了
The partner might have killed him for it.
好想法  大侦探  你看
Nice going, Sherlock. See?
我们配合得多好
We make a perfect team.
走吧
Let's go.
怎么了
What was that?
什么怎么了
What was what?
看看这个
Hey, check this out.
交通摄像头拍到维克多把车停在
Traffic cam caught Victor parked a block away
距离芯片被偷处一个街区之外的地方
from where the microchip was stolen.
这就是维克多  就在行窃发生前
That is Victor right before the burglary.
还有一个人跟他一起
And there's someone with him.
肯定是他搭档  有更清楚的画面吗
Must be a partner. Is there a better look?
没有
Nope.
那个人会不会是斯勒特
What if that's Slaughter?
我跟他的警监谈过
I spoke to his captain.
斯勒特被调出了黑帮组
Slaughter was reassigned from gangs
因为有个毒贩指控他
because a dealer accused him
在一次突袭时中饱私囊了两万块钱
of pocketing 20k during a drug bust.
据说  斯勒特就要被停职了
Word is, Slaughter was about to be suspended --
很有可能被开除
quite possibly kicked off the job.
也就意味着拿不到退休金了
Which means "Bye-bye, pension."
偷这个芯片
The microchip burglary
可能就是斯勒特为退休做的打算
might have been Slaughter's retirement plan.
如果维克多想要出卖他
And if Victor tried to double-cross him...
斯勒特会干掉他
Slaughter would have put him down.
可是为什么要把卡塞尔牵扯进来呢
But why involve Castle in all of this?
可能维克多在死前把芯片藏起来了
Maybe Victor hid the microchip before he died.
斯勒特找不到
Slaughter couldn't find it.
所以他想骗卡塞尔
And so he thought he could fool Castle
用他特别的大脑来帮忙找出来
into using his unique brain to help him find it.
幸运的是
Well, it's a good thing
卡塞尔不至于那么笨相信他
Castle's not dumb enough to fall for that.
你觉得芯片会在哪
So, where do you think the chip is?
如果维克多的搭档没有把它买给特鲁科
If Victor's partner didn't sell it to Trucco,
那有可能还在他那里
then they probably still have it.
这位天才是谁
Who's the talent?
斯勒特  这位是海莉
Slaughter, this is Hayley.
怪不得你对那个慕男狂室友没兴趣呢
No wonder you weren't interested in that nympho roommate?
什么意思
I'm sorry -- what?
没什么
Just... forget it.
海莉刚开始跟我合作  是我的顾问
Hayley just started working with me as a consultant.
是的  里克之前让我
Yes, Rick has asked me
调查一下布斯塔的入室盗窃案
to suss out the break-in at Booth Tower.
英式英语  很性感
Oh, and she speaks British. That's hot.
每次认识你的朋友总是很愉快  里克
It's always a pleasure meeting one of your friends, Rick.
他真的不是...  你就无视他吧
He's really not... just... please ignore him.
你查到什么了吗
Did you find anything?
当然了
Of course I did.
布斯塔的安保系统
So, the security system at Booth Tower
非常地先进
is definitely cutting-edge.
需要天才级的数字锁专家
It would have taken a genius-level digital locksmith
才能攻破一层层的警报系统
to get through the several layers of the alarm system.
天才
Genius.
维克多或者他的那群朋友都不是天才
That sure as hell ain't Victor or anyone he hangs with.
你确定吗
You sure about that?
我调查了一下
'Cause I did some digging,
维克多之前主动为一个16岁的
and it turns out that Victor volunteered as a mentor
名叫路易斯·普林斯的穷苦孩子
to an underprivileged 16-year-old boy
当导师
named Louis Prince.
我黑进了路易斯的档案
Now, I hacked Louis' records,
他有很多次暴力犯罪记录
and he has quite the history of violence.
还被关进过少管所很多次
Turns out he's been in and out of several juvenile detention facilities,
而且还被四所高中都开除了
and he was kicked out of four high schools.
我觉得这孩子不怎么聪明
Doesn't sound too smart to me.
那是他的智商吗
Is that his I.Q.?
是的  190
Oh, yes -- 190.
这是个罪犯版的《心灵捕手》吗
It's like a criminal Good Will Hunting?
是的
Yeah.
而且他好像已经上升到杀人的地步了
And it looks like he's graduated to murder.
路易斯的生活很不幸
Louis had a rough life.
他五岁的时候被父亲抛弃
He was abandoned by his father when he was 5,
由母亲抚养长大
and then he was raised by his mother,
为了养活他  他母亲打了两份工
who has to work two jobs to support him.
所以这孩子一天有20个小时都是自己生活
Kid was on his own 20 hours a day.
不是所有的留守儿童都成了杀人凶手
Not all latchkey kids wind up killers.
是的  他们也不都像爱因斯坦那么聪明
Yeah, they're not all Einstein-level geniuses, either.
说实话  路易斯简直太聪明了
Louis was -- honestly was just too smart.
而且也没人告诉他该怎么培养自己的天赋
And he didn't have anyone to help nurture his talents,
所以他就胡作非为
so all he could do was lash out.
那时我第一次见到了他
That's when I first met him.
我当时立刻就意识到他是导师行动的
I knew right away he was the perfect candidate
最佳人选
for Operation Mentor.
而他最需要的就是一个
What he needed more than anything
强大的男性榜样来照看他
was a strong male role model to look out for him.
-也就是维克多  -最后才是他
- That was Victor. - Eventually, yes,
路易斯之前接触过五个导师
But Louis went through five other mentors first.
我顶着很大压力没让他出局
I got a lot of pressure to kick him out of the program.
维克多是我最后的希望
Victor was my last shot,
不过他们一见面就非常合得来
but they hit it off right away,
而且路易斯也开始慢慢变好
and Louis started getting better.
警探  其实你应该考虑当导师
You know, detective, you should consider becoming a mentor.
我可不是什么当榜样的材料
Yeah, I'm not role-model material.
真的不是
He's really not.
谁也说不好  我也不是一直做顾问
You never know. I wasn't always a counselor.
我以前为了赚钱在华尔街每天工作15小时
I used to chase money around Wall Street for 15 hours a day,
可来到这里  更适合我
But this here -- this is definitely more fulfilling.
是的  我想也是
Yes, I imagine so.
如果维克多想利用路易斯的天赋
Now, if Victor were to use Louis' genius
来帮他犯罪  这样就是
to help commit a crime, that would have been
完全背叛了他的信任  对吧
quite a betrayal of trust, wouldn't it?
是否足以让他爆发然后杀了他的导师呢
Enough to make him snap and kill his mentor?
除了路易斯的妈妈  维克多是第一个能够取得
Well, Victor was the first person that Louis ever trusted,
他信任的人
besides his mom,
所以如果发现维克多背叛了他
So finding out he'd been betrayed
他会感到非常绝望的
would have been pretty devastating.
知道路易斯会藏在哪里吗
Any idea where Louis might be hiding?
我不知道  抱歉
I don't know. Sorry.
谢谢你的配合  韦斯特先生
Thank you very much for your time, Mr. West.
我们得走了
W- we got to go -- now.
是的  谢了
Yeah, thanks.
韦斯特先生  我是莱恩警探
Mr. West. I'm Detective Ryan.
这位是埃斯波西托警探  纽约警局的
This is Detective Esposito. NYPD.
我们想问一些有关路易斯·普林斯的问题
We just have a few questions about a kid
他的导师是维克多·李
that Victor Lee was mentoring named Louis Prince.
他可能知道一些信息
It's possible he might have some information
能帮我们破一个案子
that can help us solve a crime.
真有意思  有两个警察
That's funny -- you guys just missed
刚刚离开这里
the two other cops that were here.
他们也来问路易斯的事
They were asking about Louis, too.
好的  知道了
Yes. Got it.
海莉利用路易斯电脑的IP地址
Hayley managed to track Louis down
找到了他的行踪
using the I.P. address on his computer.
我知道地址了
I have an address.
非常感谢你  海莉
Thank you very much for doing this, Hayley.
我有电话打进来了  谢谢
I- I have another call. Thanks.
我是卡塞尔
This is Castle.
你骗了我们
You lied to us?
要是这么说的话...
Well, when you put it that way...
卡塞尔  我不是跟你开玩笑
Castle, no. This is not funny.
你跟谋杀案嫌犯混在一起干什么
What are you doing running around with our murder suspect?
斯勒特没杀人  好吧
Hey, Slaughter didn't kill anyone, all right?
我向你们保证
I promise you.
他和我们一样想找到杀维克多的凶手
He wants to find Victor's killer just as much as we do.
是吗  他跟你说了为什么不在罪案组了吗
Really? Did he tell you why he's not working gangs anymore?
是的  他说太无聊了
Yes -- he said he got bored.
不  他是被降职了
No. He got demoted.
他因为抢了毒贩的钱正在接受调查
He's under investigation for robbing a drug dealer.
你抢了毒贩的钱吗
You robbed a drug dealer?
没有  那个指控简直是扯淡
Oh, hell no. That's a B.S. charge.
斯勒特就要失去退休金了  卡塞尔
Slaughter's about to lose his pension, Castle.
我们认为他是跟维克多合伙去偷那个芯片
We figure that he teamed up with Victor to steal that chip,
然后他想独吞
and then he got greedy.
把电话给我
Give me that.
警探  少管闲事
Hey, detective, get your head out of our butt!
是的  我的确是修理了一下维克多
Yeah, sure, I might have tuned Victor up a little bit,
不过我没杀他
but I didn't kill him.
你们查我就是在浪费时间
You're wasting your time chasing after me.
你们应该去找那个孩子
You should be after the kid.
喂
Hello?
你知道把SIM卡拿出来就行了  对吧
You know you can just take the S.I.M. card out, right?
干这行后我丢的手机更多了
I lose more phones in this line of work.
如果我想退出  你会同意的  对吧
If I wanted to just walk away, you would let me, right?
不想干了吗
Having second thoughts?
鉴于以前的事  我觉得这合情合理
I think that's reasonable, given your history.
你是指咱俩以前的事
You mean given our history.
不许动
Freeze!
陪着这孩子  大侦探
Stay with the kid, Sherlock.
别紧张  别紧张  我们是来帮你的
Relax, relax. We're not here to hurt you.
求你了  求你离我远点
Please. Please stay away from me.
过来
Come here.
没事了
You're okay. Come on.
我们正试图弄清楚维克多出了什么事
We're just trying to figure out what happened to Victor.
我没杀他  我发誓
I didn't kill him. I swear.
没人说是你干的
No one's saying you did.
不是吧
Really?!
觉得有点丢脸了吧
Not your proudest moment, huh?
我认为不是他干的
I don't think he did it.
当然是他干的
Sure he did.
你没看到他的表情
You didn't see his face.
他很害怕  他还这么年轻
He was scared and young.
那不是一个凶手会有的神情
It's not the face of a killer.
到危急关头时我们都是凶手  卡塞尔
We're all killers, Castle, when push comes to shove.
走
Come on.
我还需要表现得和善吗
Do I still have to play nice?
不用了
No.
很好
Good.
现在你告诉我们你来这干什么
Now, you're gonna tell me what you're doing here,
否则我会把你老二像拉链一样  拉到你下巴
or I'm gonna pull your dipstick up to your chin like a zipper.
我为那小子来的
Okay, I came for the kid.
为什么
Why?
因为他是关键人物
'Cause he's the key.
-我要开始拉了  -不  等等
- I'm gonna start zipping. - No, wait!
我在一个专偷高端公司的团伙混
Look, I work for a crew that specializes in high-end B&Es,
老板叫大卫·雷西
run by a guy named David Lacey.
我知道雷西
Ugh. I know Lacey.
他坏了反社会人士的名声
He gives sociopaths a bad name.
你们帮维克多偷微芯片吗
So you guys helped Victor steal the microchip?
不是
No.
他开始侮辱我们的智商了
See, now he's insulting our intelligence.
把浴帘拿来
Go get the shower curtain.
这会弄得一滩血的
This is gonna get a little messy.
别  是真的
No, no, it's true!
维克多和那小子独自完成了微芯片的盗窃
Victor and the kid pulled off the microchip job alone --
为了传递一个信息
to send a message.
什么样的信息
What kind of message?
维克多四处散播
Victor was going around town
说他有可以开启任何锁的钥匙
boasting that he had the key to any lock.
是指路易斯吗
Meaning Louis?
那孩子发明了一种可以使任何警报器失效的系统
The kid invented a device that could disarm any alarm system,
不管多复杂都可以
no matter how complex.
闯入布斯塔是为了引起世人关注
So breaking into the Booth Tower put the town on notice
维克多的装置就可以招来出价更高的买家
that Victor's services were available to the highest bidder.
维克多在利用路易斯
So Victor was using Louis.
可是你的老板雷西
Only your boss, Lacey,
没兴趣跟维克多讨价还价
wasn't interested in paying Victor's price.
于是维克多一死  你来这
So Victor ends up dead, you come here,
免费带走这个孩子
pick up the kid free of charge.
斯勒特
Slaughter!
把手举起来
Put your hands up right now.
马上
Do it -- now.
小心点  我的武器可比你的火力猛
Easy with that. It's a little more weapon than you're used to.
是啊
Yeah.
你有权利保持缄默
You have the right to remain silent.
是啊  知道  早就听说过了
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Heard it all before.
需要再来一队人押送另一个嫌犯
We're gonna need another unit to transport a second suspect.
谢谢你
Thank you.
埃斯波  他没杀维克多
Espo. Espo. He didn't kill Victor.
如果我的直觉正确的话  也不是路易斯干的
And if my instincts are right, neither did Louis,
那就意味着一个16岁的孩子独自在外面
which means there is a 16-year-old kid out there alone
一群非常危险的人在追踪他
with a very dangerous crew after him.
我们需要调集全部人手来寻找他
We're gonna need all hands on deck to find him.
那是不可能的  卡塞尔
It's not gonna happen, Castle.
-斯勒特跑不掉了  -可他们
- Slaughter's going in. - But they --
你该庆幸我没以协助教唆罪
And you're lucky I don't arrest you, too,
把你也一起抓起来
for aiding and abetting.
-埃斯波  求你了  -不行  卡塞尔
- Espo, please. - No, Castle.
我不会改变主意的
I'm not changing my mind on this.
莱恩
Ryan.
莱恩  另一组人到哪了
Ryan, where are we with that other unit?
-搞什么  -对不起
- What the hell? - I'm sorry. I'm s--
对不起  我不该那样做的
I'm sorry. I shouldn't have done that.
刚才发生了什么
What just happened?
卡塞尔偷走了我们的嫌犯
Castle just stole our murder suspect.
还有我们的车
And our car.
-你笑什么  -你笑什么
- What are you laughing at? - What are you laughing at?
哈维  我想他们知道了
Javi, I think they know.
他们不知道
They don't know.
不  巡逻队的人完全相信了
No, that patrol unit totally bought our story
我们说车出故障了的说辞
about our car breaking down.
把他关起来
Yo. Take him to holding.
过来
Hey. Come here.
可如果下班时
What happens when we don't get the
车还送不到调配场怎么办
car back to the motor pool at the end of our shift?
我觉得该给贝克特打电话
I think we should call Beckett.
说什么  说她丈夫
And tell her what -- that her husband
在我们鼻子底下把越狱犯带走了吗
staged a jailbreak right under our noses?
其实是在你鼻子底下
Well, technically, your nose.
但那  那不是重点
But that -- that's not the point.
我们必须找到卡塞尔和斯勒特
We just need to find Castle and Slaughter.
在想好下一步该怎么办之前待在这里很安全
We'll be safe here till we figure out our next move.
这不可能是你家吧
This can't be your place.
为什么不能是
Why not?
两个原因  第一  我们都是逃犯
Two reasons -- one, we're both fugitives.
藏身于我们任何一个人的家中
Hiding at either of our apartments
都是个糟糕的主意
would be a terrible idea.
第二  我以为你家里会更《枪与弹药》风
Two, I picture your decor less architectural digest,
而不是《建筑文摘》风
more guns & ammo.
是我前妻的家  她出城了
It's my ex-wife's. She's, uh, out of town.
我不知道你结过婚  她叫什么
I had no idea you were married. What's her name?
麦迪
Maddie.
我猜麦迪很喜欢看歌剧
And I take it Maddie's a fan of the opera?
她是纽约歌剧院的女中音
She's a mezzo-soprano at the New York City Opera.
你是说麦迪是玛德琳·科尔黛
I'm sorry -- "Maddie," as in Madeleine Corday?
我看过她的表演
I've seen her perform.
她  她简直太棒了
She -- she's an absolute revelation.
我只是无法想象她...
I just can't picture her...
跟你在一起
...with you.
你们是怎么认识的
How did you even meet her?
大学
College.
我们俩一个专业
We had the same maj--
你的专业是歌剧演唱吗
You majored in opera singing?
不是
No.
音乐剧表演
Musical theater.
-你吗  -是的
- You? - Yeah.
如果你敢告诉别人
And if you tell anyone,
我就把你的脾塞到你鼻子里
I'm gonna force-feed you your spleen through your nose.
对不起  我尽量表现得害怕来着
Yeah, I'm sorry. I'm trying to be scared.
只是我还在想象你摆爵士手造型
I just keep picturing you doing jazz hands.
卡塞尔在哪
Where's Castle?
不知道
I have no idea.
别骗我们  我们没心情跟你闹
Don't lie to us. We're not in the mood.
是啊  我们不得不打私家车来
Yeah, we had to Uber here.
什么  你们的车呢
What? Where's your car?
那不重要
That's... not important.
重要的是我们必须要找到他  立即马上
What is important is that we need to find him -- now.
我们已经几个小时没见到他了
Well, we haven't seen him for hours.
出什么事了
What's going on?
我们逮捕斯勒特后  卡塞尔偷了我们的车
Castle stole our car after we arrested Slaughter.
真抱歉
I-I'm sorry.
那真的不好笑
That's, uh, that's really not funny.
真的很好笑啊
It really is, though.
好了  别笑了
Okay, knock it off.
等等  你们为什么逮捕斯勒特
But wait, wait. Why did you arrest Slaughter?
我爸爸说  他没杀维克多·李
According to dad, he didn't kill Victor Lee.
-那不是重点  -那好像就是重点
- That's not the point. - It's kind of the point.
我们有理由相信
Look, we had reason to believe
斯勒特杀了维克多  但是
that Slaughter killed Victor, but --
现在我们...  不确定了
Now we're... not so sure.
我可以告诉你们  那个天才少年路易斯
Well, I can tell you this -- that genius kid Louis
绝对没杀他
definitely didn't kill him, either.
你怎么知道的
How do you know that?
我帮卡塞尔追踪他的IP地址时
While I was tracking his I.P. address for Castle,
注意到在凶案发生的时段里
I noticed that during the time of the murder,
路易斯在布鲁克林的一个咖啡店里
Louis was at a coffee shop in Brooklyn.
一个店员记得曾见过他
And a barista remembers seeing him.
也就是说大卫·雷西是我们的头号嫌犯
Which makes David Lacey our prime suspect.
这个雷西是谁
Who's this Lacey guy?
他操纵一伙劫匪  杀了很多人
He runs a heist crew -- with a trail of bodies.
我们抓了他的一个手下  他什么也不肯说
We've got one of his soldiers in holding, and he's not talking.
等等  我爸爸有危险吗
Wait -- is my dad in danger?
我们真的得找到他
We really need to find him.
尽快
Fast.
味道好极了
Yum, yum, yum, yum.
来  尝尝这个
Here. Try that.
-你到底是什么人  -是啊
- Who are you? - Yeah.
我下厨的时候可以很好地思考
I do some of my best thinking when I'm cooking.
我就是这样度过了离婚的那段日子
It's what got me through my divorce.
你和麦迪出了什么事
What happened with you and Maddie?
她的事业越来越成功
Her career took off.
而我的一开始就失败了
Mine failed to launch.
我嫉妒了
I got jealous.
从那以后就每况日下
Went downhill from there.
你和你妻子到底怎么了
What really happened with you and your wife?
我说了  我不知道
I told you -- I don't know.
你那么聪明  可不该说这样的话  大侦探
You're too smart to be talking this stupid, Sherlock.
如果你真的爱那个妞
If you really love that broad,
就想办法弄清楚问题在哪
you figure out what the problem is,
然后解决它
and you do something.
是那个孩子
Hey, it's the kid!
老天  怎么又是你
Oh, God. Not you again.
我要找斯勒特警探
I'm looking for Detective Slaughter.
-他在这儿  - 嗨
- yeah, he's -- - hey.
维克多告诉我  如果有麻烦了就来找你
Victor told me that if I ever got into trouble to find you.
他说你能保护我
He said that you'd look out for me.
他是这么说的
He did?
我是说  是的  我当然会保护你
I mean, y-yeah, yeah. 'course I will.
等一下  你是怎么找到他的
Wait a minute. How did you find him here?
我  我黑了他的资料
I-I hacked his life.
你干了什么
You what my life?
我做了一个密码生成器
I used a cryptographic generator I created
用它搞到了你的社保号码
to get your Social Security number.
然后就是简单的推算了
After that, it was simple guesswork.
我查看了你的信用卡消费记录和银行账户
I went through your credit cards, your bank statements,
我发现你有一个前妻
and when I discovered that you had an ex-wife
她最近在意大利表演
who's currently performing in Italy, I found it odd
奇怪的是她家的警报系统刚刚被关掉了
that her home alarm system had recently been disarmed.
我破了几道防火墙  查了你前妻的日程表
I knocked down a few firewalls, got into your ex's calendar,
发现管家周四之前不会过去
and discovered the housekeeper doesn't come until Thursday,
所以我猜一定是你
so I assumed it was you.
我黑了她的电脑IP地址  就这样
I hacked her desktop's I.P. Address, and here I am.
也许我应该叫他"大侦探"
Maybe I should be calling him "Sherlock."
有人来了
Someone's here.
告诉我们你的位置  然后我要你躲起来
Hey, kid, tell us where you are, and then I want you to hide.
我在  在一个仓库
I'm -- I'm in a warehouse --
该死的  没信号了
Damn it. We lost him.
也许不会  你看那面墙
Maybe not. Look at the wall.
那是什么
What is that?
蒸汽警告
Fumigation notice.
而且可以辨认公司的名字
And you can just make out the company name
还有电话号码
and the phone number.
我真的觉得我们应该叫后援
I really think we should call for backup.
去他的后援  我们走
Ah, screw that. Come on.
我看见那孩子了  他被绑在椅子上
I see the kid. He's tied to a chair.
看起来他在受审问
Looks like he's being interrogated.
有几个人
By how many?
我只看见一个  我们上
I only see one. Come on.
你连把枪都没有
You don't even have a gun.
只有一个人  走吧
It's just one guy. Come on.
嗨  哥们
Hey, buddy.
-干得漂亮  -小菜一碟
- nice. - piece of cake, huh?
怎么啦  孩子
What's the matter, kid?
看来我们该叫上后援的
Guess we should have called for backup.
马后炮
Do you think?
傻货们  杀警察对于你们的犯罪记录
OK, chuckleheads, killing a police officer's
可不是什么好的补充材料
not exactly a good addition to your rap sheet.
或是杀畅销作家
O-or a best-selling author.
如果谁也找不到你们的尸体
It's kind of hard to charge us with murder
要控告我们谋杀貌似有点难
if nobody ever finds the bodies.
要我把那小孩先弄出去吗
Should I take the kid out of here?
不用  让他看着
Nah, let him watch.
这样也好让他明白如果不照我说的做
This way, he knows what's gonna happen to him
他会有什么样的下场
if he doesn't do exactly what I ask.
你他妈的在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
停下来
Hey, knock it off!
大侦探  我们就要死在这儿了
Sherlock, we're gonna die here.
我们好歹试着死得爷们一点行吗
Let's at least try to do it like men, huh?
男孩  男孩  疯狂的男孩
Boy, boy, crazy boy
冷静  男孩
Get cool, boy
你的口袋里有一块石头
Got a rocket in your pocket
保持冷静  男孩
Keep cooly cool, boy
别激动  哥们  还有好日子在前头
Don't get hot 'cause, man, you got some high times ahead ?
男孩  男孩  疯狂的男孩
Boy, boy, crazy boy
放轻松  男孩
Stay loose, boy
吹吹小风  放轻松  不是很容易吗
Breeze it, buzz it, easy does it ?
-谁来打死这两个家伙  -打开那果汁  男孩
- Will somebody please shoot these guys! - Turn up the juice, boy
打斗场面开始
Fight scene!
抱歉
Sorry.
不许动
Don't move!
把手举起来
Show me your hands!
就这些
Is that it?
你就带来这么点人吗
Is that all the guys you brought?
你觉得我们乐意这样吗
You think we enjoy this?
谢谢你来找我
Hey, uh, thanks for coming for me.
维克多没看错人
Victor wasn't wrong about you.
没错  但是我看错了他
Yeah. But I was wrong about Victor.
他是个糟糕的榜样
He was a crappy role model.
你是个糟糕的歌手
And you're a crappy singer.
你们搞定雷西一伙了吗
You nail Lacey and his crew?
是的
Yeah.
他们因为绑架和试图谋杀
They'll be doing some serious time
得蹲很长一段时间的牢房了
for kidnapping and attempted murder.
为什么他们没有被控告谋杀
Why aren't they getting charged with actual murder?
因为他们谁都没杀维克多
Because none of them killed Victor.
维克多被害的时候
They were at a restaurant in SoHo
他们都在苏活区的一家餐厅
at the time of victor's homicide.
就是说我们又回到原点
So we're right back to square one.
倒不会
Not necessarily.
路易斯  你还记得任何关于维克多死时的事吗
Louis, is there anything you can remember about Victor's death?
没有了  我发誓
Nothing. I swear.
但是你和维克多  你确实用你的设备
But you and Victor -- you did use your device
进入了布斯大厦然后偷走了那个芯片  对吧
to break into Booth Tower and steal that microchip, right?
维克多带着这个主意来找我
Victor came to me with the idea.
他受够了拿那点薪水生活
He was sick of living paycheck to paycheck,
他承诺把芯片卖给布斯的竞争对手后
promised to split the profit that we got
我们把得来的钱对半分
from selling the chip to Booth's competitor,
那样我就可以照顾我妈了
and I could take care of my mom for once.
但是他没来取芯片
But when he didn't show up for the chip,
我不知道该怎么办
I didn't know what to do.
等一下  芯片在你那里
Wait -- you have the chip?
这是你们计划好的吗
And was that part of the plan?
不  我们从大厦离开的时候
No, when we were leaving the tower,
维克多开始表现得有点奇怪
Victor started getting all weird.
为什么  发生了什么事
Why? What happened?
我不知道  但是他更改了原计划
I don't know, but he deviated from our plan.
他告诉我拿好那个芯片
He told me to hang on to the chip
他还说他晚点儿跟我汇合
and that he would catch up later.
他说他得去办一些事儿
Said he had to... take care of some business.
那可能是为了一个干更大的一笔
That's probably part of the bigger score.
更大的一笔什么
What bigger score?
真不想告诉你这些  孩子
Hate to tell you, kid.
闯入大楼从一开始就不是为了偷芯片
That break-in was never just about stealing that microchip.
那是向全城的抢劫团伙打广告
It was an advertisement to all the heist crews in town.
为你的发明打广告
For your invention.
维克多在利用你
Victor was using you.
我要跟负责人谈话
Hey, I need to speak to somebody in charge.
布斯先生  我是莱恩警探
Mr. Booth. I'm detective Ryan.
这位是埃斯珀西托警探
This is detective Esposito.
那就是闯进我大楼的那个混蛋
So, that's the punk who broke into my building,
他让我变成了一个笑话
Turned me into a late-night punch line, huh?
我们找回了您的芯片
We recovered your microchip.
谁在乎芯片
Who cares?
我们能私下谈谈吗
A word in private?
可以
Yes.
先生们  你们知道
Gentlemen, as you know,
我是纽约警局的一位慷慨的支持者
I am a generous supporter of the NYPD,
无论是警察球队或者寡妇和孤儿基金我都支持
Be it the policeman's ball or the widows and orphans fund.
布斯先生  您需要我们为您做什么吗
Mr. Booth, is there something you need from us?
帮我个忙
A favor.
-我想  是一个需要很谨慎的忙  -是的
- A discreet one, I take it. - Yes.
竞争对手先把芯片推向市场
The money I'd lose if a rival brought
使我损失的那笔钱
a version of that microchip to market before me
比起那小子从大楼偷走的真正财富
pales in comparison to the real fortune
简直一文不值
that punk kid stole from my building.
什么财富
What fortune is that?
今天早些时候  我的一个开曼群岛的账户
Earlier today, $50 million was wired
划走了五千万美元
from a cayman islands account I have.
-一个私人账户  -你是说秘密账户
- a private account. - you mean a secret account.
是的  背着我太太  那账户需要继续保密
Yeah -- from my wife. It needs to stay that way.
所以我需要你们无论如何
So I need you to do whatever it takes
找回我的钱并且避免更多的丑闻
to recover my money quietly to avoid further scandal.
明白吗
Do you understand?
你为什么觉得是那孩子偷了你的钱
What makes you think this kid stole your money?
还有谁有机会这么干
Who else could have?
账户号码  转账密码
Account number, the transfer codes --
都被保存在一个电子保险箱里
They were kept in an electronic safe in my office two floors up
就在他偷走芯片的无菌室两层楼以上
from the clean room where he stole the microchip.
我是说  那孩子是个天才
I mean, the kid's a genius.
他有一个设备可以开我的锁  不是吗
Got a device that can open any lock, right?
我对什么开曼账户一无所知
I don't know anything about a cayman account,
而且我发誓我没偷什么五千万美金
And I sure as hell didn't steal $50 million!
路易斯  哥们  对我们说实话
Louis, come on, man. Be straight with us.
是的孩子  如果你拿了那笔钱  首先  厉害
Yeah, kid, if you took that money, first of all, impressive,
更重要的是  你得坦白
but more importantly, you got to fess up.
听着  不是我拿的
Look, it wasn't me.
伙计们  我想他说的是实话
Guys, I think he's telling the truth.
如果路易斯偷了钱
If Louis stole the money,
他一开始为什么会去向斯勒特求援
why would he go to Slaughter for help in the first place?
我们为什么会在一个仓库里找到他
Why would we find him hiding in a warehouse?
大侦探说得对  这孩子是个天才
Look, Sherlock's got a point here. Kid's a genius.
有五千万美金  我们还没来得及眨眼
With $50 million, he'd drop off the face of the earth
他就逃出地球表面了
before we could even blink.
好吧  路易斯  是否有可能
Okay, Louis, is it possible
是维克多从保险箱里偷走了密码
that Victor stole the codes from that safe?
不  不可能
No. No way.
我们在大楼里的时候他跟我一秒都没分开过
He was with me every second we were inside that building.
那到底怎么回事
So, what are we saying here?
另有他人闯进了那座大楼
Someone else broke into that building, too?
等等
Wait.
你说过当你们离开那座大楼的时候
You said that when you and Victor left the building,
他开始表现得奇怪
he started acting strange,
还改变了原计划  把芯片给你了
broke from your original plan by giving you the microchip.
是的
Yeah.
那么  也许他这么做是因为看到了什么
Well, maybe he did that because he saw something.
像是什么
Like what?
他认为自己看到了
Something that made him think
其他人尾随  利用他们的行径
that someone else was piggybacking on the burglary
干了自己的一票
to pull a heist of their own.
还有谁知道你们的计划
Who else knew about your plan?
没人
No one.
至少我没跟任何人说过
At least not from me.
但也许维克多说过
But maybe from Victor.
等一下
Hey, wait a minute.
当我们进到大楼地下室里的服务电梯时
When we accessed the building's service elevators
维克多把门用楔子顶开了
in the basement, Victor wedged the door open.
但我们走的时候  门是关着的
But when we left, it was closed.
我还以为是被风吹的
I-I-I assumed it was a draft.
有可能是别人
It could have been a second thief.
该死  肯定是这事吓到了维克多
Hot damn. That's got to be what spooked Victor.
也许当维克多说
Maybe when Victor said
他需要先处理一些事
that he had to take care of something first,
就是要去找这个贼对质
it was to confront this piggyback thief.
也就是说后来闯入的人
Which means whoever our second burglar was
不仅仅知道他们要抢劫布斯的计划
not only knew about the plan to rob Booth
还知道布斯把秘密账户的密码
but also had knowledge of where Booth kept those codes
放在哪
for his secret account.
我们找到那个人  就找到凶手了
We find that person, we find our killer.
我们漏掉了一些东西  先生们
We are missing something, gentlemen.
准确地说  我们漏掉了某个人
More specifically, we're missing someone --
某个既知道维克多和路易斯
a person who knew Victor and Louis
在计划盗窃
were planning their heist
同时又对布斯的财产了如指掌的人
and had intimate knowledge of Booth's finances.
我们的凶手
We'll find our killer
就在这个维恩图解的交集里
in the intersection of that Venn Diagram.
唯一的问题就是  那会是谁呢
Only question is, who could that be?
拜托  埃斯波西托
Oh, come on, Espo.
你不会真的准备起诉路易斯吧
You're not really gonna charge Louis, are you?
他犯了法  卡塞尔  这不是在玩大富翁
He broke the law, Castle. It's not "Monopoly".
没有"免收牢狱之灾"的游戏卡
There's no "get out of jail free" card.
重大盗窃
Grand theft.
就算他未成年  也还是要蹲监狱的
Even though he's a minor, he's looking at real time.
这孩子从头到尾就没别无选择
Kid never stood a chance.
他这辈子都被那些本应成为
All his life, he'd been taken advantage of
他模范榜样的成人所利用
by adults who should be acting like his role models.
怎么了  你有所发现吗
What's up, man? You got something?
当我问布斯先生
While questioning Mr. Booth
关于他在开曼群岛的账户时
about his Cayman Island accounts,
他说那些账户是五年前才开的
he told me that they were set up a mere five years ago.
是吗  那又怎样
Yeah? So?
猜猜谁当时在帮他开户的那家
So guess who worked at the accounting firm
会计师事务所工作
that originally set them up.
我很开心你们在路易斯遭遇不幸之前
I'm just glad you guys were able to find Louis
找到了他
before something horrible happened to him.
是啊  我们很幸运
Yes, uh, we got lucky.
请坐
Please -- uh, have a seat.
可怜的孩子
Poor kid.
他受了太多苦
He's -- he's been through so much.
路易斯案子上庭的时候
You know, I'd like to testify
我愿意当他的品行证人
as a character witness on Louis' behalf
为他出庭作证
when his case goes to trial.
你真是个好人  韦斯特先生
That's very kind of you, Mr. West.
但你那时候不会忙着自己的庭审吗
But won't you be too busy with your own trial?
我的庭审  你在说什么
My trial? What are you talking about?
我们已经知道了
We know.
知道什么
You know what?
首先  你不是一直在帮助高危青少年
Well, for starters, you didn't always work with at-risk youth.
是  我以前有别的工作  那又如何
No, I mean, I've had other jobs. So?
你曾做过布斯先生的会计
So you were Mr. Booth's accountant,
替他处理过一些最敏感的事务
where you worked on his most sensitive matters.
比如在海外银行建立避税账户
Like setting up tax shelters in offshore banks.
是的  那那份工作实在太没有成就感了
Well, yeah, but the work was unfulfilling,
于是我就离开了  因为我想回馈社会
so I left because I wanted to give back to the community.
不  你是想回馈给布斯先生的妻子
No, you wanted to give back to Mr. Booth's wife,
但她并不接受你的性挑逗
but she didn't appreciate your sexual advances,
于是布斯先生就把你给炒了
so Mr. Booth fired your ass.
你丢了工作  丢了养老金
Yeah, you lost your job, you lost your pension,
和那些优先认股权
all those stock options.
好吧  听着
All right. Listen.
我知道这段过去不光彩  但是
I know how this looks, but --
你的声誉毁于一旦
Your reputation was ruined.
你能找到的唯一工作
The only job you could get
就是帮助少年犯
was working with juvenile delinquents.
这可不是你习惯的养尊处优的生活
Not exactly the cushy life you were used to.
所以当你听说路易斯的发明时
So you heard about Louis' invention,
你看到的不仅仅是回归上流生活的途径
and you saw not only a way to get back on top...
同时也是报复那个毁了你的生活的
But also get revenge on your former boss,
前任老板的方法
who ruined your life.
所以你才说服维克多
That's why you convinced Victor
策划了那些盗窃  对吧
to pull that heist, didn't you?
这样一来你就可以跟在他后面进去
So that you could go in right behind him
盗取开曼群岛账户的密码
and steal those Cayman Island bank codes.
这是你们想象出来的故事
Well, that is an imaginative story.
有意想不到的转折  复仇
It had surprise twists, revenge.
唯一缺少的就是证据
all that's missing is the proof.
像是从你家电脑上
Like records of the bank transfers
找出的银行转账记录吗
on your home computer?
我们取得了你家的搜查令  马克
We got a warrant for your place, Mark.
我们还有你在维克多被杀当晚
We also have a credit-card receipt
你打车去他家的
for a cab ride that you took to Victor's apartment
信用卡收据
on the night he was murdered.
一切都结束了  韦斯特先生
It's over, Mr. West.
维克多本不该知道
Look, Victor wasn't supposed to know
我的计划
what I was doing, all right?
但他不知怎么发现了
But somehow he found out,
他在他家质问我
and he confronted me at his apartment.
我被吓到了
Now, I panicked, okay?
我
I...
我没想杀他
I didn't mean to kill him.
我  你们得相信我  那不是
I -- you have to believe me. That was not --
拜托  事情没那么糟  孩子
Ah, come on. It ain't that bad, kid.
我们抓到那个混蛋了不是吗
We caught the bastard, didn't we?
但我还是要进监狱
But I'm still going to prison.
我要蹲多少年
How much time am I looking at?
也许用不着
Maybe none.
什么  怎么会
What? How?
你是个好孩子  路易斯
You're a good kid, Louis.
只因为你做了几个愚蠢的决定
Too good to be rotting in a cell
就把牢底坐穿实在是太可惜了
for a few bonehead decisions.
所以从现在开始  我要亲自确保
So from now on, I'm gonna personally see to it
有人会照看你
that you got someone looking out for you --
而且你能有个很酷的榜样
that you got a cool role model.
你是说卡塞尔先生吗
You mean Mr. Castle?
不
No.
是我
Me.
真的吗
Really?
那当然
You bet.
我要做的第一件事就是我要用我的关系
First thing I'm gonna do is I'm gonna use my pull
让市长找检察官把你的刑罚
to get the mayor to ask the D.A. to reduce your sentence
减为缓刑
down to probation.
你跟市长关系这么铁
You've got that kind of clout with the mayor?
才没有呢  但卡塞尔可以
Hell no. Castle does.
我会确保他打电话给市长的
And I'm gonna see to it that he makes that call...
不然的话
Or else.
如果卡塞尔先生不照你说的做
S-so you're gonna beat up Mr. Castle
你就揍他
if he doesn't do what you ask?
还真是个好榜样啊
Some role model.
你说得对
You got a point.
看来咱俩要
Looks like the two of us are gonna have to do
互为对方的榜样了
some role modeling for each other.
怎么样
Sound good?
你又摆出那副痴情脸了
Uh-oh. You got that dumb look on your face again.
我
I...
我不知道  我只是搞不懂贝克特
I don't know. I'm just confused about Beckett.
我也搞不懂
That makes two of us.
那么漂亮的一个女人
I mean, how does a hot lady like that
怎么就爱上你了呢
fall in love with a guy like you --
尤其是当世界上
especially when there's a real man,
有我这种真男人的时候
like me, running around?
斯勒特  你给我听着
Okay, Slaughter, you know what?
你说别的都没事  但不许说贝克特
I'll take a lot of crap from you, but not about Beckett.
这对我来说不是玩笑
It's not a joke to me.
我只是想引起你的注意  大侦探
Just trying to get your attention, Sherlock.
我知道的不多
Look, I don't know much,
但我确认的是  那女人很爱你
but what I do know is that lady has it bad for you,
而你也一样
and you feel the same.
你想说的是
Your point?
不管贝克特在干吗
Whatever's going on with Beckett,
她都不该独自面对
she shouldn't have to go through it alone.
我试过了  但她不告诉我
Yes, well, I've tried. She won't let me in.
那就不要征得她的允许
Then quit asking permission.
我就是因为自己不够男人
I lost my wife
没有把我妻子的需要放在自己的前面
'cause I wasn't man enough
才失去了她
to put her needs ahead of mine.
别犯一样的错
Don't make the same mistake.
你知道吗  斯勒特
You know what, Slaughter?
别看你平时总是夸大其词  虚张声势
For all your bluster and bravado,
你实际上也是个聪明  并且敏感
you're actually a wise and, dare I say, sensitive --
你给我打住
Whoa! Hey! Stop right there.
只有你能把两个男人讨论一个女人这种事的气氛
Only you could take two guys talking about a chick
给搞得这么诡异
and make it weird.
抱歉
Sorry.
我也是
Yeah. Me too.
每一次都是
Every time.
谢谢
Thank you.
随便了  大侦探
Whatever, Sherlock.
人人美剧「在线播放」
震撼上线
欢迎前往苹果商店
及各大安卓市场下载人人美剧客户端